Guide to the Society of Medical History of Chicago Records 1830-1982
University of Chicago Library
- Series II: Historical Collections
  - Subseries 2: Biographical Files
    - Stout, Alexander Miller (Box 13, Folder 22)
    - Strong, Albert B. (Box 13, Folder 23)
    - Stuart, John J.. (Box 13, Folder 24)
    - Temple, John Taylor (Box 13, Folder 25)
    - Temple, Peter (Box 13, Folder 26)
    - Thilo, George Wilhelm (Box 13, Folder 27)
    - Thompson, Mary Harris (Box 13, Folder 28)
    - Tilley, Robert (Box 13, Folder 29)
    - Todd, James F. (Box 13, Folder 30)
    - Tope, John W. (Box 13, Folder 31)
    - Treat, Robert B. (Box 13, Folder 32)
    - Tucker, Mills (Box 13, Folder 33)
    - Van Haren, J.C. (Box 13, Folder 34)
    - Varges, Louis (Box 13, Folder 35)
    - Venne, Henry (Box 13, Folder 36)
    - Wadsworth, F.L. (Box 13, Folder 36)
    - Wadsworth, F.S. (Box 13, Folder 37)
    - Wagner, E.W. (Box 13, Folder 38)
    - Wagner, William (Box 13, Folder 39)
    - Waite, Daniel D. (Box 13, Folder 40)
    - Walenta, Rudolph (Box 13, Folder 41)
    - Wardner, Horace (Box 13, Folder 42)
    - Ware, John D. (Box 13, Folder 43)
    - Waxham, Frank E. (Box 13, Folder 44)
    - Webster, E.H. (Box 13, Folder 45)
    - Wentworth, George Wallingford (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Wescott, Austin Brooks (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Whidden, P.C. (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Wickersham, S. (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Wilcox, William LeRoy (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Willard, Alfred L. (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Willard, Simeon (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Willard, Sylvester (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Wimmermarck, Arvid (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Winer, William Dickinson (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Wolcott, Alexander (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Wyman, Walter (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - General correspondence and biographical research (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Subseries 3: Personal Papers
    - Adolphus, Philip, 1909 copy of agreement between US and Confederate surgeons, 1862 (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Bartlett, John, lecture tickets, 1848-1849 (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - Bates, Mary E., correspondence, manuscripts, reprints and clippings, 1881-1909 (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - Blount, Joseph, journal, 1845-1847 (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - Brown, C.P., Rush Medical College course notes, circa 1868- 1869 (Box 14, Folder 18-20)
    - Byrne, John A., lecture tickets, 1873-1874 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Cleveland, George H., correspondence A-Z, circa 1892-1898 (Box 15, Folder 2-11)
    - Cleveland, George H., correspondence, 1895-1901 (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Earle, Charles Warrington, correspondence and memorial publications, 1883-1884 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Ingals, Ephraim H., lecture tickets, 1869-1871 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Grimes, W.S., lecture tickets, 1872-1874 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Hard, Nichols, lecture notes and manuscripts, 1848-circa 1870s (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Hektoen, Ludwig, American Medical Association Committee on Scientific Research, organizational history, reports and correspondence, 1900-1945 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Hektoen, Ludwig, invitation to Pasteur Institute exhibition, Century of Progress, 1933 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Herrick, Josiah M., lecture ticket, 1848 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Knapp, Moses R., correspondence and recommendations, 1870- 1887 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - LeCount, Edwin R., correspondence, 1896-1918 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - LeCount, Edwin R., clippings, 1903-1935 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - LeCount, Edwin R., Ricketts Memorial Fund Committee, financial records, 1910-1911 (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Count, Edwin R., correspondence, 1913-1932 (Box 16, Folder 12-13)
    - LeCount, Edwin R., manuscripts, publications and proofs, circa 1927-1936 (Box 17, Folder 1-2)
    - Lyman, Henry M., manuscripts, 1890-1910 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Lyman, Henry M., "Modern Russian Fiction," lecture to the Irving Club, 1886 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Match, G.A., lecture ticket, 1857-1858 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - McLane, Jesse N., thesis and clinic notes, 1862-1863 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - McLean, John, correspondence, announcements and manuscripts, 1843-1912 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - McLean, John, reprints and photograph, circa 1840s-1880s (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Owens, John E., dinner invitations, 1912 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Perkins, Joseph, correspondence and reprints, 1848-1935 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Perkins, Joseph, lecture manuscripts, circa 1850s (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Rawson, Allen H., manuscript, circa 1835 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Reynolds, J.C., lecture ticket, 1869 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Sloan, M.G., lecture ticket, 1871-1872 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Tyler, John H., lecture tickets, 1851-1852 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Walker, James W., notebook, circa 1885-1905 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Walker, James W., notebook for pathology course taught at Chicago Medical College by Frank Johnson, 1891 (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Walker, James W., notebook for practice of medicine course taught at Chicago Medical College by Frank Billings, 1892 (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Walker, James W., notebook for practice of medicine course taught at Chicago Medical College by Nathan S. Davis, Jr., 1892 (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - Walker, James W., notebook for surgery course taught at Chicago Medical College by Eastman and Hessert, 1892 (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - Walker, James W., notebook for skin diseases course taught at Chicago Medical College by Zeisler, 1892 (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - Walker, James W., notebook for gynecology course taught at Chicago Medical College by E.C. Dudley, 1892 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Walker, James W., notebook for nervous diseases course taught at Chicago Medical College by Elbert Wing, 1892 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Walker, James W., notebook for mental diseases course taught at Chicago Medical College by Archibald Church, 1892 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Walker, James W., notebook for physical diagnosis course taught at Chicago Medical College by George W. Webster, 1892 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Walker, James W., notebook for skin diseases course taught at Chicago Medical College by Zeisler, 1892 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Walker, James W., notebook, 1892 (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Walker, James W., notebook for ophthalmology course taught at Chicago Medical College by C.P. Pinckard, 1893 (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - Walker, James W., notebook, 1893 (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - Walker, James W., collection of "freak doctors" cards, 1895-1905 (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - Watson, Charles A., lecture tickets and invitations, circa 1840s- 1880s (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - Watson, C.D., certificate, lecture ticket and broadside, 1876 (Box 19, Folder 11)
    - Watson, William, student signatures and lecture tickets, circa mid- 19th century (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Weaver, George H., lecture tickets and course certificates, 1880- 1888 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Weaver, George H., Chicago Medical Society correspondence, clippings and memorabilia, 1913 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Weaver, George H., honorary dinners, invitations and programs, 1913-1919 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Weaver, George H., honorary dinners, manuscripts of speeches, circa 1910s (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Weaver, George H., historic research, correspondence and Cook County Hospital documents, 1910-1913 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Weaver, George H., George H. Tebbetts correspondence, clipping and photograph, 1924 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Subseries 4: Publications
    - Bulletin of the American Medical Temperance Assocation, collection of Nathan S. Davis, 1896-1901 (Box 20, Folder 8-9)
    - Bulletin of the Society of Medical History of Chicago, 1911-1913 (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - Bulletin of the Society of Medical History of Chicago, 1916-1939 (Box 21, Folder 1-6)
    - Bulletin, Chicago School of Sanitary Instruction, 1912-1914 (Box 22, Folder 1-4)
    - Cumston, Charles G., reprints, circa 1900-1912 (Box 22, Folder 5-7)
    - Davis, Nathan S., reprints, circa 1890-1904 (Box 23, Folder 1-2)
    - Holmes, Bayard T., reprints, circa 1891-1921 (Box 23, Folder 3-4)
    - Medical Pioneer, collection of Nathan S. Davis, circa 1893-1897 (Box 23, Folder 5-7)
    - Northwestern University, Woman's Medical School, Northwestern University (Woman's Medical College of Chicago), 1896 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Senn, Nicholas, reprints, 1891-1895 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Sperry, F.M., A Group of Distinguished Physicians and Surgeons of Chicago, 1904 (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Wickersheimer, Ernest, reprints, 1920-1923 (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Reprints, periodicals and pamphlets, collection of Nathan S. Davis, circa 1870s-1900s (Box 24, Folder 5-6)
    - Reprints, periodicals and pamphlets, 1830-1910s (Box 25, Folder 1-6)
    - Reprints, periodicals and pamphlets, 1830-1910s (Box 26, Folder 1-6)
    - Reprints, periodicals and pamphlets, 1830-1910s (Box 27, Folder 1-2)
  - Subseries 5: Prints and Photographs
    - Cook County Hospital, surgeries and autopsies, collection of Samuel Slaymaker, 1888-1889 (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - Cook County Hospital, group portraits, collection of Samuel Slaymaker, 1886-1894 (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - Cook County Hospital, ward interiors, collection of Samuel Slaymaker, 1886-1888 (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - Cook County Hospital, building exteriors, collection of Samuel Slaymaker, 1884-1886 (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - Cook County Hospital, boiler room, interns' sitting room and police patrol wagon, collection of Samuel Slaymaker, 1888-1890 (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - Rush Medical College, upper lecture room and building exterior, collection of Samuel Slaymaker, 1887-1888 (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - Rush Medical College, students and lab, group outside building, collection of Samuel Slaymaker, 1885-1887 (Box 27, Folder 9)
    - Individual portraits, collection of Samuel Slaymaker, 1867-1887 (Box 27, Folder 10)
    - Portraits collection, A-D, circa 19th century-1910s (Box 27, Folder 11)
    - Portraits collection, E-W, circa 19th century-1910s (Box 28, Folder 1-6)
    - Hospital scenes, circa 1900-1910s (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - Brown, C.P., Spring Lake, Michigan residence, 1907 (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Subseries 6: Oversize Materials
    - Organizational records, Chicago Homeopathic Medical College, scrapbook presented by Lorenzo N. Grosvenor, 1888-1900 (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - Organizational records, Chicago Retreat for the Insane, casebook, 1847-1851 (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - Organizational records, Cook County Hospital, record of autopsies, 1886 (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - Organizational records, Cook County Hospital, record of autopsies, 1889 (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - Organizational records, Cook County Hospital, obstetric record, 1883-1887 (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - Organizational records, Cook County Hospital, obstetric record, 1887-1888 (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - Organizational records, Cook County Hospital Alumni Association, minutes, 1870-1896 (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - Organizational records, Medical Relief Committee, Chicago Evening Post article on Chicago Fire, 1871 (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Organizational records, Memorial Institute of Infectious Diseases, correspondence, manufacturing licenses and clippings, 1907-1910 (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - Organizational records, Practitioners' Club of Chicago, scrapbook, 1891-1899 (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - Personal papers, Hatheway, J.C., correspondence and business records, circa 1870s-1890s (Box 33, Folder 4)
    - Personal papers, Hektoen, Ludvig, notes on lectures given by Nicholas Senn, 1889 (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - Personal papers, Hermann, Ernest, equator crossing certificate, 1944 Ingals, E.F., certificates, 1869-1875 Knapp, Moses L., certificates, 1859-1872 McLean, John M., certificates, 1835 (Box 33, Folder 6)
    - Personal papers, Senn, Nicholas, letterbook, circa 1880s-1900s (Box 34)
    - Personal papers, Weaver, George H., scrapbook of materials collected for "Beginnings of Medical Education in and near Chicago," circa mid-19th century-1925 (Box 35)
    - Personal papers, unidentified student notes, circa 1869 (Box 36, Folder 1)
    - Photographs, laboratory scenes, collection of Samuel Slaymaker, 1884 (Box 36, Folder 2)
    - Photographs, J. Blount, printing plate, mid- to late-19th century (Box 36, Folder 3)
    - Framed print, 1916; Perkins's tractors mounted for display, undated (Box 36, Folder 4)